Guide to the James E. Jackson and Esther Cooper Jackson Papers TAM 347
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series XVI: Writings by Others.
  - Subseries XVI:A: American, West European Writers.
    - Gerson, Si: Remarks at Gus Hall's 70th Birthday Celebration, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 62)
    - Green, Gil: What's Happening to Labor?; The Second Draft is Better, But Not Good Enough, Undated (Box 21, Folder 63)
    - Greenberg, Jack: Law and Lawyers in the Struggle Against Racial Discrimination, Undated (Box 21, Folder 64)
    - Hall, Otto: Biography, Undated (Box 21, Folder 65)
    - Hall, Gus, Undated, 1971-2000 (Box 21, Folder 66)
    - Harris, Lem, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 67)
    - Haughton, Jim: Perspectives on Socialism - USA, Undated (Box 21, Folder 68)
    - Healey, Dorothy: Tape Transcript on Her Expulsion from C.P.; untitled work, Undated, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 69)
    - Henry, John: The Negro Worker as Trade Unionist in the 19th Century, USA, Undated (Box 21, Folder 70)
    - Heywood, Harry: For Revolutionary Position on the Negro Question, Undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Horne, Gerald: Speech (with no title), Undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Hudson, Hosea, 1968-1986 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Hughes, Langston: Du Bois: A Part of Me; My Early Days in Harlem, Undated, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Jackson, Maurice, 1980-1984, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Jacques, Geoffrey: What is Socialism?; To Save the Soul of America: Afro-Americans and the Peace Movement 1945-1983, Undated, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Johnson, Arnold: Memo on Mass Communication, Undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Jones, Claudia: Negro Women in the Fight for Peace and Freedom, Undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Kelley, Robin: 'Organizing the Natives' The International Socialist League of South Africa and the African Worker, 1916-1920; The Road to Self-Determination: Africans, The Comintern and the Communist Party of South Africa, 1921-1928, Undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - King, Martin Luther, 1956, 1981, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Kolko, Gabriel: The Decline of American Radicalism in the Twentieth Century, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Krumbein, Margaret Cowl, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Lawson, Elisabeth: History of the American Negro People 1619-1918, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Li Yu Chin: On People's Commune, Undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Lumer, Hyman: An Anti-Party Book, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Mann, Howard: Eldridge Cleaver, Soviet Policy, Anti-Imperialism; A Review of A Long View From The Left, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Marchais, George: Excerpt from Socialism For France; An Outstretched Hand to the People of France, Undated, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Marquit, Erwin: Sources for the Crisis of Socialism in Europe; Organizational Crisis of Marxism-Leninism in the USA, 1991, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Marshall, Kenneth E.: Harlem: Planning The End of the Ghetto, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Max, Steve; Ireland, Douglas: As the New Left Views Liberalism, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Meyers, George: Aristocracy of LaborTerror Down SouthMay Day Tribute to John Meyers, Undated, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Mitchell, Charlene: Speech at the Monthly Review Conference on the Future of Socialism, Undated (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Monteiro, Tony: On Paul Robeson, Undated (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Moreau, Alberto: Critical Notes on Gil Green's Revolution Cuban Style Differences in the Anti-Imperialist Movement in Latin-America; On the Latin-American Revolution, Undated, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Nelson, Burt: The Fight for Indian Survival, Undated (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Nyden, Paul: Coal Miners, Front Rankers and Grave Diggers; The Contours of Class Struggle in Appalachia, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - O'Dell, Jack: Building the Rainbow: from the Democratic 'White Primary' to the Rainbow Coalition; The Soviet Union: An Ally for Peaceuntitled document, Undated, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Ovington, Mary White: How the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Began, 1930 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Painter, Nell Irvin: Preface to 1993 Printing of The Narrative of Hosea Hudson (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Patterson, William L.: Message to the Second Annual Awards Program, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Perlo, Victor: Where Will President Gorbachev Lead the Soviet Economy?, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Perry, Pettie, Undated (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Pittman, John, 1950-1979 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Randolph, A. Philip: The Civil Rights Revolution and Labor, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Robeson, Paul: Some Reflections on Othello and the Nature of Time, 1945 (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - Rosenzwieg, Roy: Oral History and the Old Left, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - Ross, Mike: The Third Party Tradition in North Carolina, 1947 (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Rubin, Danny: Healey and Al Richmond, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - Rubin, Danny: Writings in alphabetical order, Undated (Box 22, Folder 39)
    - Rubin, Danny: Writings in chronological order, 1985-2003 (Box 22, Folder 40)
    - Shields, Art: Reader's Letter in the Evening Kiev, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - Smith, Michael Steven: The 1949 Smith Act Prosecutions; Anti-Terrorism Bill of 1996: Will it Be the New Smith Act?; Lawyers on the Left (Box 22, Folder 42)
    - Stachel, Jack, Undated (Box 22, Folder 43)
    - Stanford, Johanna: Report on Women's Liberation, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 44)
    - Steele, James, 1975-1995 (Box 22, Folder 45)
    - Stevenson, Ronnie, Undated (Box 22, Folder 46)
    - Strong, Edward T.: To the National Committee, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - Talbot, Karen: Discussions with Leaders of Peace, Labor and Women's Groups, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - Webb, Sam, Undated, 2001, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 49)
    - Wells, Harry: Lenin's Materialism and Empirio-Criticism and the Struggle Against American Pragmatism, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - Weinstone, William W., 1956-1976 (Box 22, Folder 51)
    - West, Jim, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 52)
    - Wibich, Manfred; Winter, Urs: Capitalism and Indians in the USA, Undated (Box 22, Folder 53)
    - Wieden, Peter: The Working Class and the Nation, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 54)
    - Wilkerson, Doxey A.: On the Concept 'Negro', 1951 (Box 22, Folder 55)
    - Williams, Charles: The Farm Crisis in the South, Undated (Box 22, Folder 56)
    - Williamson, John: The Negro Worker in the 'Freedom Now!' Movement, Undated (Box 22, Folder 57)
    - Winston, Henry, 1972-1983 (Box 22, Folder 58)
    - Zipser, Arthur: Fighting for Peace: The CPUSA 1919 - 1979, Undated (Box 22, Folder 59)
  - Subseries XVI:B: Soviet Writers.
    - Soviet Writers/Politicians: A - K, 1968-1979 (Box 22, Folder 60)
    - Soviet Writers/Politicians: L - Z, 1968-1991 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Soviet Writers/Politicians: Gorbachev, 1985-1990 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Soviet Writers/Politicians: Stalin (speeches), 1929, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Series XVII. Audiocassettes. (Oral History Collection 57) NOTE: This series is stored with the Library's Oral History collections.
  Scope and Contents note
  Note: the "box" number 57 refers to the separate oral history collection number assigned this material. The audiocassettes are housed with the rest of the Library's oral history collections.
  - Subseries XVII:A: Biography
    - 60th Birthday Celebration, ca.1967 (Box OH57, Folder 1)
    - Side 1: 60th Birthday Celebration - J. Jackson's Speech; Side 2: Unknown Speaker On Middle East, 1974 (Box OH57, Folder 2)
    - Esther Cooper Jackson and James Jackson talk about themselves, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 3)
    - Kathy Interviews Jack, Apr 1984 (Box OH57, Folder 2)
  - Subseries XVII:B: Lectures, Speeches
    - 125th Anniversary of the Communist Manifesto, 1973 (Box OH57, Folder 5)
    - Africa at Audubon Hall, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 6)
    - Afro-American / Black Equality, Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 7)
    - Afro-American Conference, Oct 1990 (Box OH57, Folder 8)
    - Side 1: Afro-American History / Monthly Series; Side 2: Overview of Black History, 1987 (Box OH57, Folder 9)
    - Analysis of News, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 10)
    - On Anti-Sovietism; 23rd Convention, Communist Party, U.S.A., Nov 1983 (Box OH57, Folder 11)
    - Side 1: On Anti-Sovietism Report of Jane Gloria; Side 2: Evaluation Report of Comrade Joe, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 12)
    - Black Liberation (1), Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 13)
    - Black Liberation (2), Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 14)
    - Black Liberation (3), Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 15)
    - Black Liberation (4), Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 16)
    - Black History in the U.S.A., Undated (Box OH57, Folder 17)
    - Side 1: The Bottom Line; Side 2: The Party, Apr 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 18)
    - On Brezhnev's Visit to India and The Polish Crisis and Polish Crisis, Oct 1980 (Box OH57, Folder 19)
    - Brussels Conference: Side 1: P.B. Discussion; Side 2: Summary and Motion by James Jackson, Dec 1979 (Box OH57, Folder 20)
    - Brussels Conference: Side 1: J. Jackson; Side 2: Discussion, Dec 1979 (Box OH57, Folder 21)
    - Capitalism (2), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 22)
    - On Capitalism (3), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 23)
    - Capitalism (3)National School, Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 24)
    - Capitalism and Communism, Jun 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 25)
    - Chicago Rally 63rd Anniversary C.P.U.S.A., Oct 1982 (Box OH57, Folder 26)
    - Chicano Liberation (7-8), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 27)
    - China, Jul 1988 (Box OH57, Folder 28)
    - On China, Jun 1989 (Box OH57, Folder 29)
    - Classes and the State (1)[Side 1 Starts with: Report on Lenin], Jun 1989 (Box OH57, Folder 30)
    - Classes and the State (2), Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 31)
    - Classes and State (3), Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 32)
    - Classes and State (4), Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 33)
    - Class Graduation, Jul 1974 (Box OH57, Folder 34)
    - The Class Struggle; Historical Materialism, Q and A's, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 35)
    - The Class Struggle in History (1), May 1981 (Box OH57, Folder 36)
    - Club Problems - Centralism and Leadership; Mesaba School, Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 37)
    - Side 1: Coalition Politics; Side 2: Socialism, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 38)
    - Color Purple; C.C. Meeting, Jan 1986 (Box OH57, Folder 39)
    - Commodity Production (1)National School, Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 40)
    - Commodity Production (2)National School, Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 41)
    - Commodity Production (3)National School, Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 42)
    - Commodity Production / Crisis of Capitalism (4)National School, Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 43)
    - Communist Morality (1), Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 44)
    - Communist Morality (2), Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 45)
    - The Communist Party, May 1981 (Box OH57, Folder 46)
    - On the Communist Party (5), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 47)
    - [Communist Party] Side 1: 1st Main Political Report (Weinstein, D.); Side 2: 2nd Main Political Report (Jackson, J.), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 48)
    - Communist Party, C.C. Meeting; 60th Anniversary of the Soviet Union, Dec 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 49)
    - [Communist Party], C.C. Meeting; 60th Anniversary of the Soviet Union (6), Dec 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 50)
    - [Communist Party], C.C. Meeting; 60th Anniversary of the Soviet Union (8), Dec 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 51)
    - Communist Party, C.C. Meeting; 60th Anniversary of the Soviet Union, Dec 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 52)
    - Communist Party, Plenary Meeting; 60th Anniversary of the Soviet Union, Dec 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 53)
    - Communist Party, 63rd Anniversary, Chicago, Sep 1984 (Box OH57, Folder 54)
    - Communist Party, 66th Anniversary, Detroit, MI, Sep 1985 (Box OH57, Folder 55)
    - Communist Party, 22nd Convention, Aug 1979 (Box OH57, Folder 56)
    - [Communist Party]23rd Convention, Cleveland, OH, Nov 1983 (Box OH57, Folder 57)
    - Communist Party, Plenary Meeting (4)23rd Convention, Nov 10, 1983-Nov 13, 1983 (Box OH57, Folder 58)
    - Communist Party Plenary Meeting (5)23rd Convention, Nov 1983 (Box OH57, Folder 59)
    - Communist Party, Plenary Meeting (6)23rd Convention, Plenary Meeting, Nov 1983 (Box OH57, Folder 60)
    - Communist Party24th Convention, Chicago, IL, 1987 (Box OH57, Folder 61)
    - [Communist Party]C.C. Meeting (?), Feb 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 62)
    - Communist Party; C.C. Meeting, Jun 1979 (Box OH57, Folder 63)
    - [Communist Party], C.C. Meeting - Peace, Apr 1983 (Box OH57, Folder 64)
    - Communist Party National Committee Meeting, Aug 1990 (Box OH57, Folder 65)
    - [Communist Party] National Committee, Jan 1981 (Box OH57, Folder 66)
    - [Communist Party] Plenary Session on Functioning, Feb 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 67)
    - Conference on Communism, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 68)
    - Conference on Communism, Socialism, Capitalism, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 69)
    - Correlation of Theory and Policy, May 1979 (Box OH57, Folder 70)
    - Cultural Principles (Mesaba School), Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 71)
    - The Decade of 1890's, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 72)
    - Side 1: The Decade of 1890's; Side 2: C.C. On Peace, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 73)
    - Detante (1), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 74)
    - Detante (2), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 75)
    - Dialectical and Historical Materialism (3), Feb 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 76)
    - Dialectical Laws and Categories, Jan 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 77)
    - Dialectical Materialism (1), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 78)
    - Side 1: Dialectical Materialism; Side 2: Discussion, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 79)
    - Side 1: Dialectical Materialism + Philosophy; Side 2: Dialectical Production, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 80)
    - Dialectical Materialism, Jul 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 81)
    - Side 1: Dielectical Materialism; Side 2: Historical Materialism, Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 82)
    - Dialectical Materialism East Coast Regional School, Jul 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 83)
    - Dialectical Materialism (1) What is Philosophy?, Jul 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 84)
    - Side 1: Dialectics; Side 2: Dialectics, Ethics, Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 85)
    - Dialectics and Materialism, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 86)
    - Dialectics and Materialism, Jan 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 87)
    - Discussion, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 88)
    - Discussion (3), Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 89)
    - Discussion on the Soviet Union, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 90)
    - Side 1: Discussion - Jim Jackson Black Question + C.P. - Ted Bassett; Side 2: Evolution of Black Policy - Ted Bassett, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 91)
    - Discussion (J. Jackson, D. Weinstein, R. Storey), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 92)
    - Side 1: Discussion + Report; Side 2: Lecture on Social Revolution, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 93)
    - Discussion / Political Economy: Value, Price, Profit, Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 94)
    - Side 1: Discussion; Side 2: Imperialism (Stages of), Mar 2, 1978-Mar 6, 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 95)
    - Discussion, Update, Aug 1988 (Box OH57, Folder 96)
    - Du Bois - Foster School Graduation, Apr 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 97)
    - Election, 1984 (Box OH57, Folder 98)
    - Side 1: Entertainment Industry / Blacks; Side 2: Class Struggle / Capitalism, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 99)
    - Side 1: Ethics; Side 2: Philosophy / Moral Mission, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 100)
    - Ethics (2), Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 101)
    - Ethiopian Revolution, Mar 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 102)
    - Evaluations, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 103)
    - Evaluations 4/15, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 104)
    - Evaluations, Aug 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 105)
    - Side 1: Falsifiers of Marxism (with Victor Perlo); Side 2: Ideological Falsifiers, Mar 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 106)
    - FBI 000-222 - J. Jackson's Spec. Put, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 107)
    - De Maio Discussion (?) - Jackson, Jim, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 108)
    - France Electorial, Mar 1973 (Box OH57, Folder 109)
    - Group Evaluations (tape broken), Apr 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 110)
    - Group Evaluations and Remarks, Apr 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 111)
    - Henry Winston Memorial Meeting (1), Jan 1987 (Box OH57, Folder 112)
    - Henry Winston Memorial Meeting (2), Jan 1987 (Box OH57, Folder 113)
    - Historical Materialism, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 114)
    - Historical Materialism, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 115)
    - Historical Materialism (1), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 116)
    - Historical Materialism (2), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 117)
    - Historical Materialism (3-4), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 118)
    - Historical Materialism (5-6), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 119)
    - Historical Materialism, Discussion on, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 120)
    - Side 1: Historical Materialism (2); Side 2: Philosophy (?), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 121)
    - Side 1: Historical Materialism / Reports from Students; Side 2: Remarks on Monopoly, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 122)
    - Historical Materialism, Feb 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 123)
    - Historical Materialism, Feb 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 124)
    - Historical Materialism (3), Jan 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 125)
    - Historical Materialism, Aug 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 126)
    - Historical Materialism - Side 1: Social History, Social Economy; Side 2: Origin of Species and Racism, Jan 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 127)
    - Historical Materialism (Lecture and Student Reports), Aug 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 128)
    - Historical Materialism (1) Slavery, Feudalism, Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 129)
    - Historical Materialism (2) Slavery, Feudalism, Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 130)
    - Historical Materialism (3) Slavery, Feudalism, Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 131)
    - Historical Materialism (1) National School, Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 132)
    - Historical Materialism (2) National School, Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 133)
    - Historical Materialism (3) National School, Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 134)
    - Historical Materialism, Jul 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 135)
    - Historical Materialism, Jul 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 136)
    - Side 1: Historical Materialism / Discussion; Side 2: Historical Materialism, Feb 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 137)
    - Side 1: Historical Materialism; Side 2: Report, Discussion, Feb 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 138)
    - Historical Materialism / Discussion, Feb 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 139)
    - Side 1: Historical Overview of Russian History; Side 2: Panel: New Stage of USSR WBAI, Oct 1981 (Box OH57, Folder 140)
    - History of the CPUSA: Policy on African-American Equality, 1988 (Box OH57, Folder 141)
    - History of the Struggle in the South, Aug 1974 (Box OH57, Folder 142)
    - Jewish Commission, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 143)
    - The Joel CaseStudents' Testimony + Response, 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 144)
    - Side 1: Ideology, Capitalism; Side 2: Capitalism, National School, Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 145)
    - Ideological Discussion, Jun 1989 (Box OH57, Folder 146)
    - Imperialism, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 147)
    - Imperialism (1, 2-3), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 148)
    - Imperialism (2-3, 4), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 149)
    - Imperialism (3-4), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 150)
    - Imperialism, 1973 (Box OH57, Folder 151)
    - Imperialism, Aug 1974 (Box OH57, Folder 152)
    - Imperialism, Mar 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 153)
    - Side 1: Imperialism; Side 2: Political Economy / Coroup Reports, Jul 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 154)
    - India, USSR and World Peace / On Polish CrisisD.W. Forum, NYC, Nov 1980 (Box OH57, Folder 155)
    - Inflation (2-3), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 156)
    - The Internationale, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 157)
    - Karl Marx Centennial ConferenceSpeech by J. Jackson, Mar 1983 (Box OH57, Folder 158)
    - Left Wing Communism, Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 159)
    - Left Wing Communism, Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 160)
    - Left Wing Communism and Internationalism (3), Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 161)
    - Lenin and the Revolutionary Party, Jun 1974 (Box OH57, Folder 162)
    - Lenin, Tribute to, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 163)
    - Leninist Strategy and Tactics, Feb 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 164)
    - Line of March: C.C. Meeting, Dec 1984 (Box OH57, Folder 165)
    - Line of the March, Dec 1984 (Box OH57, Folder 166)
    - Side 1: Freedomways - Nirma, Lollie, Geroge D.; Side 2: Maoism - Jackson J., Undated (Box OH57, Folder 167)
    - Maoism (2), Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 168)
    - Maoism (3), Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 169)
    - Side 1: Maoism; Side 2: Falsifiers of Marxism (with Victor Perlo), Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 170)
    - Maoism, Jan 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 171)
    - Maoism, 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 172)
    - Side 1: Martin Luther King (Hoyen, R.; Ronelle); Martin Luther King (Jackson, J.) Morality (Newcomer, S.), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 173)
    - On Martin Luther King, Jan 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 174)
    - Materialism / Dialectics, Jul 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 175)
    - Middle East, Speech onMass Rally in N.Y. versus Israel War on Palestinians, Oct 1982 (Box OH57, Folder 176)
    - Side 1: Moral Question; Side 2: Jewish Question by Spector, Danny, Apr 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 177)
    - Side 1: Moral Role; Side 2: Gay Question 3/28, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 178)
    - Side 1: Morality - Jackson, J. 3/28; Side 2: Mitchell, C. 3/29, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 179)
    - Morality, Mar 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 180)
    - Morality and Revolution, Mar 1978 (Box OH57, Folder 181)
    - Side 1: Morality (James Jackson); Political Economy (Hy Lumer); Side 2: Political Economy, Inflation (Hy Lumer), Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 182)
    - Side 1: National Question; Side 2: Trade Union, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 183)
    - National Question (1-2) (End of Maoism), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 184)
    - National Question (2), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 185)
    - National Question (3-4), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 186)
    - National Question (5-6), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 187)
    - Side 1: National Question (James Jackson); Side 2: Racism (Sylvia Newcombe), Mar 3, 1975-Mar 4, 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 188)
    - National Question Party School, Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 189)
    - National Question (2) Party School, Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 190)
    - National Question, Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 191)
    - National Question (2), Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 192)
    - National Question (3), Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 193)
    - Side 1: National Question (4); Side 2: Political Economy, Dec 12, 1975-Dec 14, 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 194)
    - National Question, Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 195)
    - National Question (Puerto Ricans, Chicanos, Indians, Asians), Dec 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 196)
    - National Question, Feb 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 197)
    - National Question (1), Jul 1976 (Box OH57, Folder 198)
    - National Question (3), Mar 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 199)
    - National Question / Political Economy Review, Dec 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 200)
    - National Question (3), Jan 1979 (Box OH57, Folder 201)
    - The Party, Undated (Box OH57, Folder 202)
    - The Party (2) [bad], Undated (Box OH57, Folder 203)
    - The Party (2-3), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 204)
    - The Party (4-5), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 205)
    - The Party (6-7), Undated (Box OH57, Folder 206)
    - On the Party, May 1981 (Box OH57, Folder 207)
    - The Party (2), May 28, 1981 (Box OH57, Folder 208)
    - Party Birthday, Aug 1977 (Box OH57, Folder 209)
    - Party History; Party School, Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 210)
    - Party History (1), Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 211)
    - Party History (2), Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 212)
    - Party History (2), Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 213)
    - Party History (3), Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 214)
    - Party History (4), Mar 1975 (Box OH57, Folder 215)
    - Party Organization with Mike Welch, Aug 1974 (Box OH57, Folder 216)
    - Side 1: Party Organization with Mike Welch; Side 2: Blank, Aug 1974 (Box OH57, Folder 217)
    - On Party Platform, May 25, 1979 (Box OH57, Folder 218)